So, hello everyone, in this video we are going to work with our sine of functions and
we are going to complete our sine of controller, okay.
So in this case, what we will do, like suppose, what is going to happen when we are going
to our chat application, so we will have some fields right, in the sine of form, we will
have the email username password of the person which is going to set, okay.
So on that basis, we are going to just extract it from the request or body, or pass it
from the body's body of the front end, okay, and we are going to get that in the backend.
So let's get it through const email username and password, okay.
So using the request or dot body, we are going to parse the email username and the password
from the user site, he is going to provide all of these fields, and now after that, we
are going to just use the try and cache block.
So in order to catch any kind of exceptions, all right.
So error, we are going to put it here error.
So in the try block, what will we do, suppose the user name is not present or the user name
is not provided, or other cases would be that if the email is not provided, email is
not provided, okay, and one another use case would be that if the password is not provided
by the user, then in that case, what will return, we will return a response.
So res dot status, and we are going to just send the 400 status code dot JSON, we are going
to send one message, that message, that all the fields are required, all the fields are
required.
Now if all of these fields are not given, and also one condition we also like to add,
like if the password dot length, if the password's length is below 6, as we have specified
in our user model, then in that case, what will happen, we are going to just return
another message, so return res dot status, and then we are going to return the message
in the form of 400 status code and dot JSON, and instead of that, we are going to just
send our message, so the message would be, the message would be password at least 6 characters,
okay.
So we need a password right, we need a password, which should be at least 6 characters.
That's why I have just written here, okay.
So after that, we are going to this cache block, like if any kind of exception error
is found, then in that case, we are going to return that error.
Similarly, like this return res dot status 400 dot JSON, in this format only, we are going
to catch the error in the cache block, and we are going to return it.
But before that, what we are going to check is, there are some other conditions that we
need to check.
Suppose what happens, like if a email is already registered or a user is already registered
and saved in a database, so we have to apply a check on that as well, right.
So const user equal to await, we are going to use await and then user dot find one, so user
dot find, so we are going to use this method, okay.
So we are going to find the user, if it is already present in the database, if it is already
registered, all right.
So, and if it does exist, then in that case, we are going to just return that this user
is already, like exist, it is already registered.
So return res dot status, and then we are just going to set the status code as 400, and
then we are going to return the message in the form of JSON format.
So message would be user already exists, okay.
So this would be the check.
So as you can see here that we need to, we are using the await here, okay.
So in that case, we are, we are going to just use this async here.
Since async and await are used like this format only, and now as you can see here that
there is no, nothing which is called as the user, okay.
So what you can do, just import user from dot slash, we are going to this model folder,
and inside of the model folder there will be user model file and apply this dot JS extension
here.
So it will be automatically fixed, okay.
So now as we can see here that for both of these conditions we are checked.
So now after that we are going to import one another package, which is called as the import
b-crypt, okay.
So b-crypt, why we are using the b-crypt, wait, I am going to tell you, we are going to use
the b-crypt in order to hash the password, okay.
So import b-crypt from b-crypt, so b-crypt JS, okay.
So import b-crypt from b-crypt JS, and now what we will do, like since we are going to hash
the password right, we are going to store a password in a hash manner, like no one should
be able to see what is the password that we have saved, okay.
So in that case a wait b-crypt dot hash, and there should be one password which we are getting
and set the salt value as 10, so it is kind of a random value which we are setting here.
So why we are using this b-crypt JS, you know, like we are using this b-crypt JS in order
to hash our passwords, so that no one can see that password in our MongoDB database, we
are using this b-crypt JS, okay.
So control has saved it, and after this what we are going to do, we are going to just create
the new user, okay.
So again, so we are going to create a new user using this has password and all, const the
new user, so new user equal to new user using the user model, and now we are going to
just take the user name from above, so user name and email, so like this we are going
to construct a new user and we are also going to save that new user in the database.
So new user dot save, so control has saved, and also one thing, like here is a password,
okay, so password should be, this has password we are taking, so hashed password, so
control has it saved.
So this b-crypt function is going to store the password in a like string format which
is unreadable, like something any random combination of digits, okay.
So that no one can read our password in the database, and it has, that's why this b-crypt
is actually used ok.